<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Image_processing on Alejandro Mottini</title>
    <link>https://amottini.github.io/tags/image_processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Image_processing on Alejandro Mottini</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Alejandro Mottini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 10:32:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amottini.github.io/tags/image_processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Axonal Tree Classification Using an Elastic Shape Analysis Based Distance</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/axonal-treeclassification-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 10:32:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/axonal-treeclassification-2014/</guid>
      <description>The analysis of the morphological differences between normal and pathological neuronal structures is of paramount importance. Some methods for the comparison of axonal trees only take into account topological information (such as TED), while others also include geometrical information (such as Path2Path). In a previous work, we have presented a new method for comparing tree-like shapes based on the Elastic Shape Analysis Framework (ESA). In this paper, we extend this method by computing the mean shape of a population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discrete Stochastic Model for the Generation of Axonal Trees</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/discrete-stochasticmodel-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 10:32:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/discrete-stochasticmodel-2014/</guid>
      <description>In this work we propose a 2D discrete stochastic model for the simulation of axonal biogenesis. The model is defined by a third order Markov Chain. The model considers two main processes: the growth process that models the elongation and shape of the neurites and the bifurcation process that models the generation of branches. The growth process depends, among other variables, on the external attraction field generated by a chemo attractant molecule secreted by the target area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Axon Extraction from Fluorescent Confocal Microscopy Images</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/axon-extraction-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 10:32:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/axon-extraction-2012/</guid>
      <description>The morphological analysis of axonal trees is an important problem in neuroscience. The first step for such an analysis is the extraction of the axon. Due to the high volume of generated image data and the tortuous nature of the axons,manual processing is not feasible. Therefore, it is necessary to develop techniques for the automatic extraction of the neuronal structures. In this paper we present a new approach for the automatic extraction of axons from fluorescent confocal microscopy images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection and Tracking of Axonal Tips from Bi-Photon Microscopy Images</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/detection-tips-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 10:32:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/detection-tips-2011/</guid>
      <description>Live cell two-photon microscopy is an effective tool for the analysis of dynamical processes occurring in living samples. This technique,when combined with fuorescence, allows the detection of objects of interest in 3D space and time. Due to the high volume of data, the automatic analysis of the images is desired. To this end, the Marked Point Process (MPP) detection framework was selected. MPP is a probabilistic framework which has been successfully applied to the detection of objects in different image processing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Software for the Detection of Epileptogenic Zones in Refractory Epilepsy</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/integrated-software-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 10:32:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/integrated-software-2010/</guid>
      <description>We present an integrated software designed to help nuclear medicine physicians in the detection of epileptogenic zones (EZ) by means of ictal-interictal SPECT and MR images. This tool was designed to be flexible, friendly and efficient. A novel detection method was included(A-contrario) along with the classical detection method (Subtraction analysis). The software’s performance was evaluated with two separate sets of validation studies: visual interpretation of 12patient images by an experimented observer and objective analysis of virtual brain phantom experiments by proposed numerical observers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>