<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine_learning on Alejandro Mottini</title>
    <link>https://amottini.github.io/tags/machine_learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine_learning on Alejandro Mottini</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Alejandro Mottini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:32:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amottini.github.io/tags/machine_learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Airline Passenger Name Record Generation using Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/gans_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:32:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/gans_2018/</guid>
      <description>Passenger Name Records (PNRs) are at the heart of the travel industry. Created when an itinerary is booked, they contain travel and passenger information. It is usual for airlines and other actors in the industry to inter-exchange and access each other’s PNR, creating the challenge of using them without infringing data ownership laws. To address this difficulty, we propose a method to generate realistic synthetic PNRs using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Choice Model Using Pointer Networks for Airline Itinerary Prediction</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/deep_choicemodel-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:32:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/deep_choicemodel-2017/</guid>
      <description>Travel providers such as airlines and on-line travel agents are becoming more and more interested in understanding how passengers choose among alternative itineraries when searching for flights. This knowledge helps them better display and adapt their offer, taking into account market conditions and customer needs. Some common applications are not only filtering and sorting alternatives, but also changing certain attributes in real-time (e.g., changing the price). In this paper, we concentrate with the problem of modeling air passenger choices of flight itineraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relative Label Encoding for the Prediction of Airline Passenger Nationality</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/relative-labelenc-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 10:28:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/relative-labelenc-2016/</guid>
      <description>In the airline industry, a Passenger Name Record (PNR) stores the travel itinerary of an individual or group of passengers travelling together. A PNR always contains all the flight information regarding each segment of a journey, and may contain additional important information such as nationality, gender and age of the passengers. From a commercial point of view, these passenger attributes are of particular interest to all actors in the travel industry (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Axonal Tree Classification Using an Elastic Shape Analysis Based Distance</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/axonal-treeclassification-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 10:32:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/axonal-treeclassification-2014/</guid>
      <description>The analysis of the morphological differences between normal and pathological neuronal structures is of paramount importance. Some methods for the comparison of axonal trees only take into account topological information (such as TED), while others also include geometrical information (such as Path2Path). In a previous work, we have presented a new method for comparing tree-like shapes based on the Elastic Shape Analysis Framework (ESA). In this paper, we extend this method by computing the mean shape of a population.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>