<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning on Alejandro Mottini</title>
    <link>https://amottini.github.io/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Learning on Alejandro Mottini</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Alejandro Mottini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:32:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amottini.github.io/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Airline Passenger Name Record Generation using Generative Adversarial Networks</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/gans_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:32:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/gans_2018/</guid>
      <description>Passenger Name Records (PNRs) are at the heart of the travel industry. Created when an itinerary is booked, they contain travel and passenger information. It is usual for airlines and other actors in the industry to inter-exchange and access each other’s PNR, creating the challenge of using them without infringing data ownership laws. To address this difficulty, we propose a method to generate realistic synthetic PNRs using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Choice Model Using Pointer Networks for Airline Itinerary Prediction</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/deep_choicemodel-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:32:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/deep_choicemodel-2017/</guid>
      <description>Travel providers such as airlines and on-line travel agents are becoming more and more interested in understanding how passengers choose among alternative itineraries when searching for flights. This knowledge helps them better display and adapt their offer, taking into account market conditions and customer needs. Some common applications are not only filtering and sorting alternatives, but also changing certain attributes in real-time (e.g., changing the price). In this paper, we concentrate with the problem of modeling air passenger choices of flight itineraries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>