<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Applied_math on Alejandro Mottini</title>
    <link>https://amottini.github.io/tags/applied_math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Applied_math on Alejandro Mottini</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Alejandro Mottini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 10:32:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amottini.github.io/tags/applied_math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Discrete Stochastic Model for the Generation of Axonal Trees</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/discrete-stochasticmodel-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 10:32:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/discrete-stochasticmodel-2014/</guid>
      <description>In this work we propose a 2D discrete stochastic model for the simulation of axonal biogenesis. The model is defined by a third order Markov Chain. The model considers two main processes: the growth process that models the elongation and shape of the neurites and the bifurcation process that models the generation of branches. The growth process depends, among other variables, on the external attraction field generated by a chemo attractant molecule secreted by the target area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree-like Shapes Distance Using the Elastic Shape Analysis Framework</title>
      <link>https://amottini.github.io/project/tree-likeshapes-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 10:32:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amottini.github.io/project/tree-likeshapes-2013/</guid>
      <description>The analysis and comparison of tree-like shapes is of great importance since many structures in nature can be described by them. In the field of biomedical imaging, trees have been used to describe structures such as neurons, blood vessels and lung airways.Since it is known that their morphology provides information on their functioning and allows the characterization of pathological states, it is of paramount importance to develop methods to analyze their shape and to quantify differences in structures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>